Futon, clothes, shoes, toothbrush?
What else?
Huh?!
Rin! Don't disappear
on me all of a sudden!
You startled me!
Okay.
Daikichi, get a green one.
Come on! Let's go.
It's dangerous if we don't hold hands.
For me?
I dunno about tomorrow.
It's different than a sacrifice. Something's off.
I don't think it's like some penalty game.
So, why? I don't get it at all.
I'm a little bit unsatisfied, but your presence
right now is more than just important.
There's no such thing in this world
as something never-ending.
Crying isn't painful, it's love's sweet drops, sweet drops!
I want to keep dreaming forever, ya know?
I want to be more kind, ya know?
As long as I’m with you, I’m happy.
Girls sure are strong, ya know?
But sometimes we're weak, ya know?
Our wish is to be happy, happy, happy!
And those days will be happy, too!
Just wanna make you happy!
I want blue!
Were there always this many
parents with their kids here?
I want that!
This?
Yeah.
Umm... Okay. Sure, why not?
What's your size, about?
I dunno.
Rin, turn around.
Like this?
What am I supposed to match it to?
I dunno!
Don't flap your arms!
What else do you wear?
Pajamas! Underwear! Shirts! Socks!
You don't need a skirt?
All you've got are pants.
Skirts aren't allowed at nursery school.
I see...
Nursery school?!
It slipped my mind!
Tomorrow's Monday!
Daikichi, I'm tired!
We're almost there, so stick it out.
Okay...
I'm hungry...
We'll be home in a minute, so...
Okay...
You useless bum!
You always bring me crap I don't need!
I'm gonna lose my temper!
You bastard!
Hey!
Don't touch me!
Let go of me!
Uh, excuse me...
Yes, this is the Maeda residence.
Oh, please accept my condolences
over your sudden loss.
Yes, please wait a moment...
Haruko-san, it's Daikichi-san.
Uh, okay. Thank you!
Oh, Haruko?
Sorry, I didn't know your cell number.
It's okay.
Tell me, how do you register
for nursery school?
Nursery school...
You really did take Rin-chan home?!
Are you sure about this?
For now...
What do you mean, "for now"?
So, anyway, I can't
take off work tomorrow.
What kind of procedures
need to be followed?
Look, you can't just
get accepted instantly.
Can you do something on your end?
What can I do?
For starters, I'd go consult
with the city office...
It's Sunday night.
What?
Nothing, it's over here.
Mama, is that Rin-chan?
Is everything okay?
Rin-chan!
Reina, please!
This is important!
Rin-chan!
There's an emergency
temporary nursery school...
Emergency temporary nursery school...
Rin-chan!
What? Dai-chan?
Rin-chan! Rin-chan! Rin-chan! Rin-chan!
Nothing, it's over here.
I'm almost done, so wait!
I hate waiting!
Haruko-san, I'm going to
turn off the miso soup.
Okay! Thank you.
Hey... It sounds like you're
busy, so I'll call back later...
Rin-chan!
Emergency Temporary
Nursery School
Man, there's hardly any of them...
So, my commute time is
suddenly doubled...?
Yeah. Yeah. I'm good.
This one's pretty close, but I can't
get out of the office by six...
Let's play again.
Yeah. Bye-bye, Reina-chan.
Talk to you later!
This looks like a good one,
but they'll accept kids on an
emergency basis for only 10 days...
Bath...
Just wait a little longer...
Daikichi! Daikichi!
It's morning...
Yeah... Sorry...
Did you sleep here?
The futon is weirdly warm.
Take this off!
Yeah, yeah.
About the nursery school
we're going to today...
Thank you for the food I'm about to eat!
Thank you for the food...
You're not supposed to eat
with your elbow on the table!
There. Sorry.
Listen, the nursery school you're going
to today is only a temporary deal.
Temporary?
Only until we find you a place that
will officially let you attend.
What's "officially"?
It means like, "for real"...
Or, not quite...
Never mind my hair!
Are you okay?
I'm fine...
F-Fine...
I see it!
Put me down! Put me down!
What? What?
Would you be embarrassed if other
kids saw me carry you or something?
Daikichi...
Yeah...
Well, please take good care of her.
Sure. We'll see you later.
Don't look at me like that!
I won't be able to make it back
while it's still light out,
but I'll come as fast as I can.
I promise.
Pinky swear.
If I lie, I swear
I'll swallow 1000 needles...
Dammit!
My finger was cut off!
That's not how the song goes!
Well, see ya! Wait for me here, Rin.
I'm sorry, Rin.
I didn't take your feelings
into consideration.
You had nothing to do with your
mother's circumstances or Grandpa's lifespan,
and yet you were left behind
with the lonely reality.
Did you think I was going
to leave you behind too?
I'm sorry.
I'll never let that
happen to you again...
Read it to me.
Sure.
Kawachi-san. Wanna get some lunch?
I brought this.
I need to leave a little early today...
Oh, yeah? Then I'll see you in a bit.
Working really hard from the
beginning of the month, huh?
That's not it.
Take a photo of this sample.
Okay.
Kawachi-san! You've got a call from
outside line #4, about the private viewing.
Coming.
Hello, this is Kawachi.
Bye-bye!
Let's keep going!
Yeah.
Kawachi...
Yes! Excuse me...
You're late!
Sorry about that. Go and put
your regular clothes on.
All right!
Rin-chan, don't break it, okay?
Yeah...
Bye-bye!
Bye-bye...
Kawachi-san, let's grab some dinner.
Yes, please wait one moment.
Kawachi-san.
It's Miyata-san from Mitsutomo Trading.
Hand it over...
Hello, this is Kawachi.
Thank you for your patronage.
Hello, Kawachi here.
Yes...
I'm terribly sorry.
Yes. I'll be able to leave my company
in a few more minutes, so...
I'm sorry.
This nursery school is so far!
Rin! Sorry I'm late!
Welcome back!
I'm really... sorry.
Rin...
Are those potatoes?
They look delicious.
It's burdock!
Daikichi
I swallowed
1000 needles!
Please take care of this.
Kawachi-san! I need your signature!
Not like I need to worry,
but what'll happen if
I get a girlfriend?
Daikichi! Daikichi!
Wake up!
Okay... Sorry...
Kawachi, this is what you
sent out yesterday, isn't it?
I'm so sorry...
It's unusual for you...
Sorry...
I already apologized
to the recipient, so...
Sorry... I'll call.
We haven't gone out drinking
for a while. What do you say?
Sorry, tonight's no good.
Then, how about tomorrow?
I've got something tomorrow, too...
Oh, I get it! Good for you, you sly dog.
Here.
I'm fine!
Daikichi!
Hold on tight!
Daikichi! Run away from the moon!
No end to this!
How long can I keep up this lifestyle?
Mother-Child Health Record Book
These are Rin-chan's.
This is all she has,
but her mother and child health
handbook and important documents are in here.
Even if it's only for
a short period of time,
raising a child is a
very difficult thing.
It's Rin who has it
the most difficult...
Sorry. I'm just gonna take a peek...
She's got the same mouth...
All the relatives are talking about
you like you're some foul villain.
But I wonder what the truth is...
Masako-san.
A sunny early Sunday afternoon
Let's go somewhere today
It's the same road I'm used to traveling
But I can see it sparkling so bright
With the sun shining down its warmth
And you here by my side...
I'm already high, high, high
I feel like dashing out
Sing, la, la, la
My voice out to forever
I'm already high, high, high
Ride the dancing wind
Sing, la, la, la
My voice springs up
What's wrong?
You feel bad someplace?
In fact, you're sleeping
over there now...
M-Me?! Me?!
It's sweat!
Sure, sure... It's sweat.
Sweat...
Help me take the sheet off.
I said it's sweat!
I'm saying it's sweat too, aren't I?!